<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/AU/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/AU/1/</guid>
      <description>Page 1 for Australia </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Acquired-immune-deficiency-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Acquired-immune-deficiency-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>Acquired immune deficiency syndrome Version: April 2024
Introduction Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome (AIDS) is a chronic, life-threatening condition caused by the Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV). It degrades the immune system, preventing the body&amp;rsquo;s ability to combat other viruses, infections, and diseases. The virus is transmitted through direct contact with certain bodily fluids of a person who has HIV. Symptoms differ in different stages, from flu-like problems in early stages to severe illnesses in advanced stages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Acute-hemorrhagic-conjunctivitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Acute-hemorrhagic-conjunctivitis/</guid>
      <description>Acute hemorrhagic conjunctivitis Version: April 2024
Introduction Acute hemorrhagic conjunctivitis (AHC) is a highly infectious, rapidly spreading ocular disease manifested by the reddening and swelling of the conjunctiva - the clear, thin tissue covering the white of the eye and the inner surface of the eyelids. Symptoms include eye pain, light sensitivity, and blurred vision. It&amp;rsquo;s primarily caused by the enterovirus (EV70) and coxsackievirus A24 variant. Despite its alarming appearance, the condition is generally self-limiting, typically resolving without treatment within 7 to 14 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Anthrax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Anthrax/</guid>
      <description>Anthrax Version: April 2024
Introduction Anthrax is a severe and potentially fatal disease caused by Bacillus anthracis, a spore-forming bacterium. It primarily affects livestock and wild game, but humans can get infected through exposure to infected animals or their products. Anthrax comes in three forms: cutaneous (skin), inhalation (lungs), and gastrointestinal (digestive system). Cutaneous is the most common and least deadly, whereas inhalation anthrax is the most lethal. Anthrax is not contagious but it is a potential biological weapon due to the longevity and survivability of its spores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Brucellosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Brucellosis/</guid>
      <description>Brucellosis Version: April 2024
Introduction Brucellosis is a zoonotic infection caused by the bacterial genus Brucella. It primarily affects animals like cattle, goats, pigs, and dogs, but humans can contract the illness through the consumption of contaminated animal products or direct contact with infected animals. Its symptoms in humans include fever, fatigue, joint pain, and sweating. Brucellosis is a significant public health issue worldwide, especially in rural, agricultural regions. The disease can be prevented through the consumption of pasteurized dairy products and use of personal protective equipment in high-risk activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Cholera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Cholera/</guid>
      <description>Cholera Version: April 2024
Introduction Cholera is an infectious disease caused by the Vibrio cholerae bacterium. It primarily affects the intestinal tract and is characterized by severe diarrhea, vomiting, and dehydration. Cholera transmission occurs through contaminated water or food consumption. The disease is a major health problem in many developing countries where access to clean water and sanitation facilities are limited. Quick rehydration is the core treatment strategy, supplemented by antibiotics when necessary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Dengue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Dengue/</guid>
      <description>Dengue Version: April 2024
Introduction Dengue is a mosquito-borne viral infection prevalent in tropical and subtropical climates worldwide. The disease is caused by four closely related viruses, the Dengue viruses 1-4. There are two forms of disease, Dengue fever and Dengue hemorrhagic fever. Typical symptoms include high fever, severe headache, and joint pain. It can advance to the severe form, leading to bleeding, blood plasma leakage, or organ impairment. The Aedes aegypti mosquito, commonly found in urban environments, primarily transmits it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Diphtheria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Diphtheria/</guid>
      <description>Diphtheria Version: April 2024
Introduction Diphtheria is a serious bacterial infection typically affecting the mucous membranes of the nose and throat. The disease is caused by the bacterium Corynebacterium diphtheriae and is primarily spread through person-to-person contact and respiratory droplets. Symptoms typically manifest as a thick, gray membrane covering the throat and tonsils, sore throat, fever, and swollen glands. If left untreated, Diphtheria can cause severe complications, such as damage to the heart, kidneys, and nervous system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Dysentery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Dysentery/</guid>
      <description>Dysentery Version: April 2024
Introduction Dysentery is an intestinal infection causing severe diarrhea with blood or mucus. Being highly infectious, it&amp;rsquo;s usually transmitted through contaminated food or water. There are two main types: Bacillary dysentery, caused by Shigella bacteria, and amoebic dysentery, caused by Entamoeba histolytica, a parasite. Symptoms include stomach pain and frequent, urgent bowel movements. If untreated, it can lead to dehydration, critical illness, and even death. Treatment pertains to maintaining hydration, adequate nutrition and, if severe, antibiotics may be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Echinococcosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Echinococcosis/</guid>
      <description>Echinococcosis Version: April 2024
Introduction Echinococcosis, also known as hydatid disease, is a parasitic infection caused by Echinococcus tapeworms. The disease occurs worldwide, primarily affecting livestock and humans. It is transmitted by the ingestion of Echinococcus eggs through contaminated food, water or direct contact with an infected animal. The infection often results in cysts in organs like the liver and lungs, causing various symptoms including abdominal pain, cough and chest discomfort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Epidemic-hemorrhagic-fever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Epidemic-hemorrhagic-fever/</guid>
      <description>Epidemic hemorrhagic fever Version: April 2024
Introduction Epidemic hemorrhagic fever is a severe infectious disease caused by hantaviruses. Primarily transmitted by rodents, it is characterized by sudden onset of fever, chills, headache, backache, and severe prostration, followed by symptoms including low blood pressure, acute shock, vascular leakage, and acute kidney failure. The disease is of primary concern in East Asian countries, though it has global prevalence. It requires immediate medical intervention to prevent mortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Filariasis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Filariasis/</guid>
      <description>Filariasis Version: April 2024
Introduction Filariasis is a tropical, infectious disease caused by Filariae - thread-like nematode worms in the family Filarioidea. It&amp;rsquo;s transmitted through a mosquito bite, circulating the parasite into the human lymphatic system. There are two primary types: lymphatic Filariasis (LF) and Onchocerciasis. LF, also known as elephantiasis, leads to the chronic enlargement of body parts, causing massive swelling and debility. Onchocerciasis, also known as river blindness, affects the skin and eyes, leading to severe itching, disfiguring skin conditions, and even blindness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Gonorrhea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Gonorrhea/</guid>
      <description>Gonorrhea Version: April 2024
Introduction Gonorrhea is a sexually transmitted infection (STI) caused by the Neisseria gonorrhoeae bacterium. It primarily infects the mucous membranes of the urethra, cervix, rectum, throat, and eyes. Symptoms may include painful urination, abnormal discharge, sore throat, and, in women, pelvic pain. However, many individuals show no symptoms. Without treatment, gonorrhea can lead to serious health problems like pelvic inflammatory disease and infertility. It can be prevented through safe sexual practices and successfully treated with antibiotics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Hand-foot-and-mouth-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Hand-foot-and-mouth-disease/</guid>
      <description>Hand foot and mouth disease Version: April 2024
Introduction Hand, Foot, and Mouth Disease (HFMD) is a contagious viral illness primarily affecting young children. It&amp;rsquo;s most commonly caused by Coxsackievirus A16. Symptoms include sores in or on the mouth and rashes on hands and feet. It spreads through coughing, sneezing, or close contact, and can also spread through contact with infected stools or surfaces. There is no specific treatment, care focuses on relieving symptoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Hepatitis-A/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Hepatitis-A/</guid>
      <description>Hepatitis A Version: April 2024
Introduction Hepatitis A is a highly contagious liver infection caused by the Hepatitis A virus (HAV). It usually spreads through the ingestion of food or water contaminated by feces from an infected person. Symptoms often include fatigue, nausea, abdominal pain, loss of appetite, and jaundice. However, not everyone shows symptoms. Vaccination can prevent the disease and is particularly recommended for those at high risk or traveling to areas with high prevalence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Hepatitis-B/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Hepatitis-B/</guid>
      <description>Hepatitis B Version: April 2024
Introduction Hepatitis B is a viral infection that attacks the liver, causing acute or chronic disease. The virus is transmitted through exposure to blood, semen, or other body fluids of an infected person. High-risk groups include those who have unprotected sexual contact, share needles, or are exposed to it at birth. Symptoms include jaundice, fatigue, nausea, and liver damage. Since the late 1980s, a vaccine has been available to prevent the spread of the disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Hepatitis-C/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Hepatitis-C/</guid>
      <description>Hepatitis C Version: April 2024
Introduction Hepatitis C is a viral infection that primarily affects the liver, leading to both acute and chronic illnesses. It is caused by the Hepatitis C virus (HCV), which is transmitted through direct contact with infected human blood. Consequences range from a mild illness lasting only a few weeks to serious, lifelong illnesses like cirrhosis or liver cancer. Globally, an estimated 71 million individuals have chronic Hepatitis C infections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Hepatitis-D/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Hepatitis-D/</guid>
      <description>Hepatitis D Version: April 2024
Introduction Hepatitis D, also known as Delta Hepatitis, is a serious liver disease caused by the Hepatitis D virus (HDV). HDV is contracted through direct contact with infected blood. It&amp;rsquo;s a unique virus because it can only infect people already infected with Hepatitis B, leading to a co-infection or a superinfection. It can cause severe symptoms and complications, including cirrhosis and liver cancer. Vaccination for Hepatitis B can provide protection against Hepatitis D as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Hepatitis-E/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Hepatitis-E/</guid>
      <description>Hepatitis E Version: April 2024
Introduction Hepatitis E is a liver disease caused by the Hepatitis E Virus (HEV). It&amp;rsquo;s typically transmitted through contaminated water or food, particularly undercooked pork or deer meat. Symptoms include jaundice, fatigue, and nausea, sometimes leading to severe complications like liver failure. Although there are four genotypes affecting humans, the disease is most prevalent in East and South Asia. Currently, there&amp;rsquo;s no specific treatment available; instead, supportive care is provided to manage symptoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Hepatitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Hepatitis/</guid>
      <description>Hepatitis Version: April 2024
Introduction Hepatitis is an inflammatory condition of the liver, commonly caused by viral infections but can also stem from toxins or an auto-immune process. There are five types - A, B, C, D, and E. Each one differs in the method of transmission and impacts on health. Though some types can lead to chronic diseases or even liver cancer, vaccines for hepatitis A and B aid in prevention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Human-infection-with-H5N1-virus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Human-infection-with-H5N1-virus/</guid>
      <description>Human infection with H5N1 virus Version: April 2024
Introduction Human infection with H5N1 virus, also known as avian influenza or bird flu, is a highly pathogenic disease that primarily affects birds but occasionally crosses species barriers to infect humans. Infected individuals typically present symptoms of severe respiratory illness, such as pneumonia. The World Health Organization reports a high mortality rate for H5N1 in humans with over 50 percent of cases resulting in death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Human-infection-with-H7N9-virus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Human-infection-with-H7N9-virus/</guid>
      <description>Human infection with H7N9 virus Version: April 2024
Introduction H7N9 is a bird flu strain of the species Influenza virus A. First reported in China in 2013, it primarily affects poultry. Transmission to humans has been associated with direct exposure to infected poultry or contaminated environments. Most infected individuals experience severe respiratory illness, including pneumonia and acute respiratory distress syndrome. Despite its high mortality rate among humans, H7N9 virus does not easily transmit from person to person, limiting its potential to cause a pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Infectious-diarrhea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Infectious-diarrhea/</guid>
      <description>Infectious diarrhea Version: April 2024
Introduction Infectious diarrhea, caused by viruses, bacteria, or parasites, is a common condition that results in frequent, loose, or watery stools. It primarily spreads through contaminated food, water, or person-to-person contact, often resulting in outbreaks in communities. Symptoms typically include abdominal cramps, fever, and nausea. Although it&amp;rsquo;s usually self-limiting, it can cause serious complications like dehydration, particularly in vulnerable populations such as children and the elderly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Influenza/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Influenza/</guid>
      <description>Influenza Version: April 2024
Introduction Influenza, commonly known as the flu, is a highly contagious viral infection often confused with a common cold due to similar symptoms. It primarily affects the respiratory system, causing fever, sore throat, muscle aches, cough, and fatigue. There are four types of influenza - A, B, C, and D. Influenza A and B are most common in humans and pose serious public health risks, leading to annual epidemics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Japanese-encephalitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Japanese-encephalitis/</guid>
      <description>Japanese encephalitis Version: April 2024
Introduction Japanese encephalitis (JE) is a mosquito-borne viral disease endemic to parts of Asia and the Pacific. Transmission primarily occurs in rural agricultural regions where flooding irrigation is used. The JE virus can cause inflammation of the brain leading to high fever, disorientation, coma, seizures, and even death. Vaccines are available for protection against JE, but no specific antiviral treatments exist. Human cases can be reduced by controlling mosquito populations and avoiding bites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Kala-azar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Kala-azar/</guid>
      <description>Kala azar Version: April 2024
Introduction Kala azar, also known as visceral leishmaniasis, is a parasitic disease transmitted through the bite of infected female sandflies. Caused by the Leishmania parasite, the disease primarily attacks the internal organs, such as the liver, spleen, and bone marrow. Its symptoms include fever, weight loss, anemia, and an enlarged spleen or liver. Without prompt and effective treatment, Kala azar is typically fatal. Predominantly found in tropical and subtropical regions, the World Health Organization has identified it as a neglected tropical disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Leprosy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Leprosy/</guid>
      <description>Leprosy Version: April 2024
Introduction Leprosy, also known as Hansen&amp;rsquo;s disease, is an infectious disease caused by the bacterium Mycobacterium leprae. The disease primarily affects the skin, peripheral nerves, and mucosal surfaces of the upper respiratory tract. Leprosy is characterized by skin lesions and progressive nerve damage, which may lead to disability. It is transmitted through droplets from the nose and mouth during close, frequent contact with untreated cases. Leprosy has a long incubation period, often manifesting 2-10 years after exposure and it can be effectively treated using multi-drug therapy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Leptospirosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Leptospirosis/</guid>
      <description>Leptospirosis Version: April 2024
Introduction Leptospirosis is a bacterial disease that affects both humans and animals. It is caused by bacteria of the genus Leptospira. In humans, it can cause a wide range of symptoms, and some infected persons may have no symptoms at all. Symptoms of leptospirosis include high fever, severe headache, chills, muscle aches, and vomiting, and may include jaundice, red eyes, abdominal pain, diarrhea, or rash. If the infection is not treated, the patient could develop kidney damage, meningitis, liver failure, and respiratory distress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Malaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Malaria/</guid>
      <description>Malaria Version: April 2024
Introduction Malaria is a life-threatening disease caused by parasites transmitted to humans through the bites of infected female Anopheles mosquitoes. Five parasite species cause malaria in humans, with Plasmodium falciparum being the most deadly. The disease is prevalent in tropical and subtropical regions. Symptoms, including fever, headache, and chills, appear 10-15 days post-infection. Without prompt and effective treatment, malaria can lead to severe illness and death. Despite significant progress, there were 409,000 malaria-related deaths in 2019, according to the World Health Organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Measles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Measles/</guid>
      <description>Measles Version: April 2024
Introduction Measles is a highly contagious viral disease prevalent in children. It&amp;rsquo;s caused by the measles virus and transmitted via airborne droplets from infected individuals. Major symptoms include fever, cough, white spots inside the mouth, and a skin rash. Despite the availability of an effective vaccine, measles still causes significant morbidity and mortality worldwide, particularly in areas with low vaccination rates. Serious complications can include blindness, encephalitis, severe diarrhea, and pneumonia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Meningococcal-meningitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Meningococcal-meningitis/</guid>
      <description>Meningococcal meningitis Version: April 2024
Introduction Meningococcal meningitis is a severe bacterial infection of the membranes that enclose the brain and spinal cord, known as the meninges. It&amp;rsquo;s caused by the Neisseria meningitidis bacterium. The disease is associated with high mortality rates and serious health complications among survivors. It spreads mainly through respiratory droplets or close contact, often causing outbreaks in crowded conditions. Although it can occur at any age, it primarily affects infants, adolescents, and young adults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Monkey-pox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Monkey-pox/</guid>
      <description>Monkey pox Version: April 2024
Introduction Monkeypox is a rare viral zoonosis endemic in Central and West African countries, caused by the Monkeypox virus. It closely resembles human smallpox and is transmitted to humans from animals, primarily rodents and monkeys. Human-to-human transmission can occur, albeit less commonly. Symptoms include fever, headache, muscle aches, rash, and chills. The disease typically self-resolves within weeks, but severe and sometimes fatal complications can occur, particularly in individuals with weakened immune systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Mumps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Mumps/</guid>
      <description>Mumps Version: April 2024
Introduction Mumps is a highly contagious viral illness, characterized by the swelling of salivary glands. Early symptoms often include fever, body aches, fatigue, and loss of appetite. The disease primarily spreads through saliva or mucus from the mouth, nose, or throat of an infected person. The Mumps, Measles, and Rubella (MMR) vaccine is used as a preventive measure against this illness. Complications can include infections of the brain, or inflammation of the ovaries or breasts in females and testicles in males.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Neonatal-tetanus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Neonatal-tetanus/</guid>
      <description>Neonatal tetanus Version: April 2024
Introduction Neonatal tetanus is a life-threatening bacterial infection affecting new-born infants, generally caused by unhygienic delivery and cord-care practices. The bacterium, Clostridium tetani, enters the body through a fresh wound, often the umbilical stump, and releases a toxin leading to severe muscle stiffness and spasms. Despite being preventable through immunization and clean birthing practices, the disease is prevalent in under-resourced regions where such amenities are not widely available and contributes significantly to neonatal mortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Other-hepatitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Other-hepatitis/</guid>
      <description>Other hepatitis Version: April 2024
Introduction Other Hepatitis refers to inflammation of the liver caused by varied strains of hepatitis viruses not explicitly categorised under the commonly known forms (A, B, C, D, E). This includes, but is not limited to, hepatitis F and G, or those caused due to autoimmune conditions or medication-induced. It may result in either acute or chronic infections leading to serious liver damage, liver failure or even cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Pertussis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Pertussis/</guid>
      <description>Pertussis Version: April 2024
Introduction Pertussis, commonly known as whooping cough, is a highly contagious bacterial infection caused by Bordetella pertussis. It notably affects the respiratory tract and is characterized by severe coughing fits that often end in a &amp;ldquo;whooping&amp;rdquo; sound during the intake of breath. It primarily spreads through droplets from coughing or sneezing. Although vaccines have significantly reduced its prevalence, pertussis remains a public health concern in many parts of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Plague/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Plague/</guid>
      <description>Plague Version: April 2024
Introduction Plague is a serious, potentially lethal infectious disease caused by the Yersinia pestis bacteria. It primarily affects rodents like rats and spreads to humans through infected fleas&amp;rsquo; bites. The disease manifests in three forms: Bubonic, characterized by swollen lymph nodes; Septicemic, affecting the blood; and Pneumonic, targeting the lungs. The plague has historically caused widespread pandemics, most notably the Black Death in the 14th century. Today, it can be treated effectively with antibiotics if detected early.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Poliomyelitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Poliomyelitis/</guid>
      <description>Poliomyelitis Version: April 2024
Introduction Poliomyelitis, commonly known as polio, is a highly infectious viral disease predominantly affecting children under 5. The virus is transmitted person-to-person, usually through contaminated water or food. It invades the nervous system, potentially causing total paralysis in hours. Tragically, 5 to 10% of those experiencing paralysis die when their breathing muscles become immobilized. Despite there being no cure, polio is preventable with multiple doses of the polio vaccine, which has reduced worldwide cases by over 99% since 1988.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Rabies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Rabies/</guid>
      <description>Rabies Version: April 2024
Introduction Rabies is a fatal viral disease primarily transmitted through the bite of an infected animal, often dogs. The rabies virus invades the central nervous system, causing disease in the brain and ultimately, death. Symptoms include fever, muscle weakness, and aggression. Despite being preventable through vaccination and proactive care, rabies continues to result in tens of thousands of deaths annually, particularly in regions with limited access to healthcare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Rubella/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Rubella/</guid>
      <description>Rubella Version: April 2024
Introduction Rubella, commonly known as German measles, is a contagious viral infection best known for its mild distinctive red rash. The rubella virus, spread mostly through airborne droplets from the nose or throat, typically affects children, causing symptoms like fever and headache. Though usually mild in children and adults, Rubella can pose severe risks to unborn babies when expecting mothers contract the virus, particularly during the first trimester, potentially causing congenital rubella syndrome, which can lead to heart defects, loss of hearing and eyesight, and other lifelong conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/SARS-CoV/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/SARS-CoV/</guid>
      <description>SARS-CoV Version: April 2024
Introduction Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus (SARS-CoV) is a viral strain that initially surfaced in 2002 in Guangdong, China. It belongs to the coronavirus family, known to cause illnesses ranging from the common cold to more severe diseases. SARS-CoV is zoonotic, crossing from animals to humans. It is responsible for the highly infectious disease, SARS, marked by severe respiratory illness, fever, cough, and pneumonia. Notable for high infection rates, SARS-CoV prompted a global epidemic in 2003, infecting over 8,000 and causing 774 deaths worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Scarlet-fever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Scarlet-fever/</guid>
      <description>Scarlet fever Version: April 2024
Introduction Scarlet fever, also known as scarlatina, is an infectious bacterial disease affecting mostly children. It is caused by Streptococcus pyogenes, or group A beta-hemolytic streptococci (GABHS). Symptoms include high fever, sore throat, red rashes on the body, and a characteristic red &amp;lsquo;strawberry&amp;rsquo; tongue. It was once a dangerous illness but is now easily treatable with antibiotics. The disease spreads through respiratory droplets in a manner similar to the common cold or the flu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Schistosomiasis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Schistosomiasis/</guid>
      <description>Schistosomiasis Version: April 2024
Introduction Schistosomiasis is a parasitic disease caused by Schistosoma species of flatworms. It is primarily transmitted through contact with contaminated water, where parasite larvae penetrate human skin. Though acute infections can be asymptomatic, chronic disease can cause damaging immune reactions, typically affecting the bladder, kidneys, liver, or intestines. It is prevalent in tropical and subtropical regions, particularly in poor communities without access to clean water and sanitation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Syphilis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Syphilis/</guid>
      <description>Syphilis Version: April 2024
Introduction Syphilis is a sexually transmitted bacterial infection caused by the bacterium Treponema pallidum. It progresses in four distinct stages: primary, secondary, latent, and tertiary. Symptoms vary with each stage, starting from sores and rashes in the early phases to serious organ damage in the later stages. Additionally, a special form, congenital syphilis, can be passed from pregnant women to their fetus. Syphilis is typically diagnosed via blood tests and can be effectively treated with antibiotics, specifically penicillin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Tuberculosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Tuberculosis/</guid>
      <description>Tuberculosis Version: April 2024
Introduction Tuberculosis (TB) is a contagious infection primarily affecting the lungs, caused by the bacterium Mycobacterium tuberculosis. It&amp;rsquo;s spread through airborne droplets when an infected individual coughs or sneezes. TB can also impact other organs and is distinguished by symptoms like prolonged cough, weight loss, fever, and night sweats. Despite it being a preventable and curable disease, TB remains a significant global health issue, affecting millions of individuals annually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Typhoid-fever-and-paratyphoid-fever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Typhoid-fever-and-paratyphoid-fever/</guid>
      <description>Typhoid fever and paratyphoid fever Version: April 2024
Introduction Typhoid and paratyphoid fever are infectious diseases caused by the bacteria Salmonella typhi and Salmonella paratyphi, respectively. Both illnesses are characterized by high fevers, abdominal pain, and other severe symptoms, transmitted through contaminated food, water, or close contact. They remain major health concerns worldwide, particularly in developing regions with poor sanitation. While antibiotics are effective treatment options, vaccination provides the best preventive measure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/CN/Typhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/CN/Typhus/</guid>
      <description>Typhus Version: April 2024
Introduction Typhus is a disease caused by rickettsial bacteria and transmitted by lice or fleas. It has two major types: epidemic and endemic (or murine). Epidemic typhus, spread by body lice, can cause high fever, delirium, and even death. Murine typhus, spread by fleas from rats, is usually less severe. Symptoms typically include fever, headache, and rash. Vaccines exist but are unavailable in most areas. Antibiotics can effectively treat typhus if diagnosed early.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
